<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="../icons/substructure.png" type="Other">
    <name>Formula Filter</name>
    <shortDescription>
        
    </shortDescription>
    
    <fullDescription>
        <intro>
               <p>This node accepts a table with molecules and a table with a gross formula strings, and splits the first table
               into three sets, the first one is with all rows that satisfy the specified relation, the second is with all
               rows that do not, the last one gathers all the rows with invalid data.</p>
               <p>Formula A is less than another formula B if A's atoms set is a subset of B's atoms set where
	           quantity of each atom in the A's subset is less than or equal to corresponding quantity of atom 
	           in formula B (even if the sets A and B are equal). For instance, a molecule of methan is less than 
	           or equal to a butane molecule as [C, H] atoms set of butane contains the same set of methan's atoms and quantity of each atom 
	           of methan is less than quantity of atom buthane molecule (1 less than 4, 4 less than 10).
               </p>
		        <p>
		        <b>Supported types:</b> 
		        <ul>
				<li>Molecule:  String, SDF, Smiles, CML, Mol, InChI</li>
				</ul>
				</p>
               <p>The node is based on the <a href="http://lifescience.opensource.epam.com/indigo">Indigo</a> cheminformatics toolkit.</p>        
        </intro>
        
        <option name="Target column">The column that contains molecule structures.</option>
        <option name="Query column">The column that contains the gross formula strings.</option>
        <option name="Relation">Relation that needs to be satisfied for all gross formulas or at least for a specified number of them.</option>
        <option name="Append queries row ID column">The column that contains all the meeting the conditions rows. </option>
        <option name="Append match count column">The column that contains the appropriate molecules amount.</option>
        <option name="Input type">Treat input as: a molecule</option>
        <option name="Treat X as pseudoatom">Treat the "X" atoms in Molfiles as pseudoatoms, not as "any halogen" query atoms</option>
        <option name="Ignore stereochemistry errors">Ignore incorrectly specified stereochemistry on input structures, rather than sending
        the structures with stereochemistry errors to the "invalid molecules" table.</option>
    </fullDescription>
    
    <ports>
        <inPort index="0" name="Input data">Table containing a column with molecules</inPort>
        <inPort index="1" name="Input data">Table containing a column with the gross formula strings</inPort>
        <outPort index="0" name="Matched">Rows with molecules that satisfy the relation</outPort>
        <outPort index="1" name="Unmatched">Rows with molecules that do not satisfy the relation</outPort>
        <outPort index="2" name="Invalid data">Rows with invalid data: data cannot be translated into Indigo object</outPort>
    </ports>    
</knimeNode>
